SUDHANSHU KULKARNI

🕲 My Portfolio 🔘 sudhanshu.kulkarni.13@gmail.com 🛮 in linkedin.com/in/sudhanshu-kulkarni 🐧 github.com/simplysudhanshu San Francisco, CA □ +(1) 609-721 1446

I am a passionate Software Developer with a perfect blend of research-oriented and application-oriented portfolio. 3+ years of experience facilitating clean & efficient software, currently exploring the realms of HPC and Quantum Computing; with a cup of coffee, of course.

EDUCATION

May 2024

MS - COMPUTER SCIENCE, San Francisco State University

THESIS: Exploring classical and hybrid classical-quantum approaches for scalable distributed-memory parallel FFT. COURSE WORK: High Performance Computing, Quantum Computing, Data Mining, Software Engineering

April 2020

BE - COMPUTER ENGINEERING, International Institute of Information Technology (SPPU)

CAPSTONE: Satellite data analysis system employing vanilla Neural Networks and Dynamic Time Warping algorithms. COURSE WORK: Machine Learning & Al, Data Analytics, Cloud Computing, Cyber Security

</> \(\rangle \) \text{Skills}

Languages Frameworks

Python, C/C++, Java, CUDA, TypeScript, Javascript, SQL, HTML/CSS, bash.

SENSEI, Qiskit, cuQuantum, Frappe, Django, Flask, SvelteJS, NodeJS, MySQL, NoSQL.

Git, Tensorflow, Keras, SciPy/NumPy, MPI, OpenMP, Linux, AWS, GCP, Docker/Kubernetes, nginx, Power Bl. Tools



EXPERIENCE

November '22 -Present

Research Assistantship - San Francisco State University, San Francisco, CA

- > Studying the feasibility of performing scalable FFT computations "in situ" on HPC platforms for the purpose of supporting scientific data analysis workloads in exascale NERSC projects like WarpX.
- > Collaborations with scientists at Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory for active research on Perlmutter, an HPE Cray EX supercomputer, achieving at least 10x speedup in computation time compared to traditional methods.

C++ | Python | High-Performance Computing | Massively Parallel | Open Source | Scientific Computing | MPI | Cuda | GPU

May 2023 -August 2023

SDE Intern - AMAZON WEB SERVICES, Seattle, WA

- > Designed and developed an enhanced monitoring agent to be deployed on thousands of live servers worldwide as a part of the AWS CloudFront CDN services' platform team.
- > Prototyped a robust and lightweight service to ensure timely capturing and reporting of critical metrics, guaranteed to enhance service reliability by at least 10% after full-fledged deployment on AWS servers across the world.
- > Created live dashboards to provide real-time visibility into at least 70% of all the agents running on servers, improving the team's ability to maintain reliability and diagnose potential issues.

Python | Server-side scripting | Dashboarding | Scalable Development | Clean Coding | Unit Tests | Agile

August 2020 -July 2022

Software Engineer - ELASTICRUN, Pune, IN

- > Core developer of in-house ERP system to manage large-scale logistics and B2B eCommerce platform and responsible for at least 20% of the entire development workload of the 'Velocity' segment of the company.
- > Worked on heavy Python-based server-side development and business-focused client-side scripting for progressive web apps, in an agile software development environment.
- > Contributed to creating an automated testing framework for faster bi-weekly software deployments with Kubernetes and CI/CD pipelines on GitLab, which improved reliability and rate of deployments by ≈15%.

Python TypeScript Frappe Framework PWA SvelteJS Full stack Git CI/CD Technical Documentation

March 2018 -July 2018

IoT Specialist Intern - SCMIND LLC, Princeton, NJ

> Low-level development on IoT-enabled supply chain machinery to deliver performance monitoring, breakdown predictions, and sensor-based critical metrics on the Raspberry Pi microprocessor hardware to power the global analytics dashboard on PowerBI via a multi-level cloud-based pipeline.

Python | ToT | Supply Chain | PowerBI | Microsoft Azure | AWS Redshift | Raspberry Pi | Performance Optimized

NOTABLE EXPERIENCES

- > An integral member of the Early-Career Conference Committee and Review Board for the ISAV workshop at The International Conference for High-Performance Computing, Networking, Storage, and Analysis (SC23), tasked with technical evaluation and assessment of submitted research papers and complimented it with a noteworthy lightning talk on Scalable FFT project research at the conference. Peer Reviewed Abstracts: https://arxiv.org/abs/2402.01843 %
- > Contributor in the Open Source SENSEI Project as a new FFT analysis backed endpoint. %
- > Prime contributor in a project in Geo-Information System domain to perform multi-class pixel-based image classification on multispectral and temporal satellite data. Technical collaborations with scientists from ISRO, NRSC and Geospatial Design Labs, India. %